Guide to the Human Rights Watch Records: Helsinki Watch,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Holly Cartner Files
  - Subseries II.1: Country Files
    - Albania
      - Germany
        - Political parties
          - Socialist Unity Party of Germany (SED), 1992 (Box 22, Folder 16)
          - Social Democrat Party (SED), 1993 (Box 22, Folder 17)
        - Prisons, 1991-1994 (Box 22, Folder 18)
        - Publications (German), 1987-1994, (5 Folders) (Box 23, Folder 1-5)
        - Racism
          - Publications (German), 1992-1993, (2 Folders) (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
          - xenophobia, 1994 (Box 24, Folder 3)
        - Refugees
          - General, 1994 (Box 24, Folder 4)
          - Bilateral treaties, 1993 (Box 24, Folder 5)
        - Right (Political)
          - General, 1990-1995, (3 Folders) (Box 24, Folder 6-8)
          - Measures, 1994-1995 (Box 24, Folder 9)
          - Nationalism, 1994 (Box 24, Folder 10)
          - Prosecution for incitement, 1994 (Box 24, Folder 11)
          - Neo-Nazi
            - Die Republikaner Party, 1993-1994 (Box 24, Folder 12)
            - Simon Wiesenthal Center, 1993 (Box 25, Folder 1)
            - Verfassungsschutz (interior secret services for the protection of the Constitution), 1993 (Box 25, Folder 2)
        - Secret services: Surveillance, 1993 (Box 25, Folder 3)
        - STASI (East German Secret police)
          - General, 1991-1995 (Box 25, Folder 4)
          - Files (Archive), 1991-1994 (Box 25, Folder 5)
          - Insiders’ committee, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 6)
          - Prosecution--lustration, 1991-1992 (Box 25, Folder 7)
          - Publications, 1990-1992 (Box 25, Folder 8)
        - Unification
          - General, 1988-1994 (Box 25, Folder 9)
          - Economic, 1993 (Box 25, Folder 10)
          - Markovits, Inga:Last Days, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 11)
        - United Nations
          - Economic and Social Council: Commission on Human Rights, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 12)
          - Troops, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 13)
        - United States
          - American Indians
            - Pogrom (German publication), 1978-1987 (Box 25, Folder 14)
            - Pogrom, Mayday and Newsweek, 1988-1991 (Box 25, Folder 15)
          - State Department--country reports--human rights, 1992-1993 (Box 26, Folder 1)
        - Women
          - General, 1993-1994 (Box 26, Folder 2)
          - Prostitution, 1993 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - Hungary
        - List of files (Index), 1994 (Box 26, Folder 4)
        - General, 1992-1994 (Box 26, Folder 5)
        - Abortion, 1992-1993 (Box 26, Folder 6)
        - Asylum--AIDS, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 7)
        - Biographies--Sándor Sára, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 8)
        - Chronology, 1992 (Box 26, Folder 9)
        - Constitution, 1993-1994 (Box 26, Folder 10)
        - Council of Europe, 1990-1993 (Box 26, Folder 11)
        - Criminal law: General, 1993 (Box 26, Folder 12)
        - Democratic Charter, 1992 (Box 26, Folder 13)
        - Diaspora, 1992-1994 (Box 26, Folder 14)
        - Economy
          - General, 1992-1993 (Box 26, Folder 15)
          - Privatization, 1992-1993 (Box 26, Folder 16)
        - Education, 1993-1994 (Box 26, Folder 17)
        - Elections, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 18)
        - Environment, 1992-1993 (Box 26, Folder 19)
        - European Community, 1992-1994 (Box 26, Folder 20)
        - Financial aid, 1993 (Box 26, Folder 21)
        - Foreign relations
          - General, 1993-1994 (Box 26, Folder 22)
          - Albania, 1993 (Box 26, Folder 23)
          - Czech Republic, 1993-1994 (Box 26, Folder 24)
          - Germany, 1992-1994 (Box 26, Folder 25)
          - Israel, 1993 (Box 26, Folder 26)
          - Moldova, 1993 (Box 26, Folder 27)
          - Romania, 1993-1994 (Box 26, Folder 28)
          - Russia, 1993 (Box 26, Folder 29)
          - Serbia, 1992-1994 (Box 26, Folder 30)
          - Slovakia, 1992-1994 (Box 26, Folder 31)
          - Slovenia, 1992 (Box 26, Folder 32)
          - Ukraine, 1992-1993 (Box 26, Folder 33)
          - United States, 1992-1994 (Box 26, Folder 34)
        - Foreigners, 1993-1995 (Box 26, Folder 35)
        - Freedom of press
          - General, 1992-1994 (Box 26, Folder 36)
          - Laws, 1993-1994 (Box 26, Folder 37)
          - Prosecutions, 1992-1993 (Box 26, Folder 38)
          - TV, radio, 1992-1994 (Box 27, Folder 1)
        - Freedom of religion, 1993 (Box 27, Folder 2)
        - Freedom of speech, 1993-1994 (Box 27, Folder 3)
        - Government
          - General, 1992-1994 (Box 27, Folder 4)
          - List, 1993-1994 (Box 27, Folder 5)
        - Helsinki Watch
          - Missions to, 1993 (Box 27, Folder 6)
          - Press, 1993 (Box 27, Folder 7)
        - Homosexuals, 1992 (Box 27, Folder 8)
        - Immigration, 1993-1994 (Box 27, Folder 9)
        - Jews--Anti-Semitism, 1992-1993 (Box 27, Folder 10)
        - Lustration: General, 1992-1994 (Box 27, Folder 11)
        - Martin Luther King Organization, 1993 (Box 27, Folder 12)
        - Military
          - Defense, 1992-1994 (Box 27, Folder 13)
          - NATO, 1993-1994 (Box 27, Folder 14)
        - Minorities
          - General, 1992-1995 (Box 27, Folder 15)
          - NEKH (Office of National and Ethnic Minorities), 1991-1993, (2 Folders) (Box 27, Folder 16-17)
          - Germans (Romanians, Slovaks), 1992-1993 (Box 27, Folder 18)
        - Ombudsman (Law), 1993 (Box 27, Folder 19)
        - Past abuses
          - General, 1991-1994 (Box 27, Folder 20)
          - Prosecutions, 1992-1995 (Box 27, Folder 21)
          - Rehabilitation, compensation, 1992 (Box 27, Folder 22)
        - Police
          - General, 1992-1995 (Box 28, Folder 1)
          - Abuses, 1993-1994 (Box 28, Folder 2)
        - Political parties
          - General, 1992-1994 (Box 28, Folder 3)
          - Alliance of Free Democrats (SZDSZ), 1992 (Box 28, Folder 4)
          - Hungarian Democratic Forum (MDF), 1993-1994 (Box 28, Folder 5)
          - Hungarian Socialist Party (MSZP), 1994 (Box 28, Folder 6)
        - Press: General, undated (Box 28, Folder 7)
        - Privacy, 1992-1993 (Box 28, Folder 8)
        - Property, restitution, 1993 (Box 28, Folder 9)
        - Refugees, 1992-1994 (Box 28, Folder 10)
        - Religion: General, 1993 (Box 28, Folder 11)
        - Secret service, 1992 (Box 28, Folder 12)
        - Social issues, 1992-1993 (Box 28, Folder 13)
        - Soros Foundation, 1993 (Box 28, Folder 14)
        - Torture: UN Committee Against Torture, 1993 (Box 28, Folder 15)
        - United Nations--Human Rights Committee: International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights, 1993 (Box 28, Folder 16)
        - United States
          - Foreign aid, assistance, 1992-1993 (Box 28, Folder 17)
          - State Department country report, 1992 (Box 28, Folder 18)
      - Italy--Vatican, 1989 (Box 28, Folder 19)
      - Romania
        - General, 1989-1991, (3 Folders) (Box 28, Folder 20-22)
        - General, 1992-1994, (2 Folders) (Box 29, Folder 1-2)
        - Abortions, 1984-1993 (Box 29, Folder 3)
        - AIDS: General, 1990-1994 (Box 29, Folder 4)
        - Amnesty International:Urgent Action, 1989-1990 (Box 29, Folder 5)
        - Anti-Romanian sentiment, 1992 (Box 29, Folder 6)
        - Attacks on human rights monitors, 1992 (Box 29, Folder 7)
        - Capital punishment, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 8)
        - Ceausescu, Nicolae, 1985-1991 (Box 29, Folder 9)
        - Census, 1992 (Box 29, Folder 10)
        - Children
          - General, 1993-1994 (Box 29, Folder 11)
          - Adoption, 1991-1994 (Box 29, Folder 12)
          - AIDS, 1990-1993 (Box 29, Folder 13)
          - Orphanages, 1990-1993 (Box 29, Folder 14)
        - Chronology, 1992 (Box 29, Folder 15)
        - Civil society, 1990-1991 (Box 29, Folder 16)
        - Committee for Human Rights in Romania: Statement, 1994 (Box 30, Folder 1)
        - Conferences in and on Romania--human rights, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 2)
        - Constitution
          - General, 1990-1992 (Box 30, Folder 3)
          - Draft, 1991 (Box 30, Folder 4)
          - Referendum, 1991-1992 (Box 30, Folder 5)
        - Cornea, Doina, 1993 (Box 30, Folder 6)
        - Council of Europe, 1990-1994 (Box 30, Folder 7)
        - Criminal procedure
          - General, 1990-1993 (Box 30, Folder 8)
          - Draft Penal Code, 1990-1994 (Box 30, Folder 9)
        - Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe (CSCE): Helsinki Commission, 1991 (Box 30, Folder 10)
        - Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe (CSCE): Romania and the Final Act, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 11)
        - Cox, Philip S, Sources of Human Rights Violations in Romania (American Foreign Policy Institute), 1986 (Box 30, Folder 12)
        - Economy
          - General, 1990-1994 (Box 31, Folder 1)
          - Aid, 1991-1993 (Box 31, Folder 2)
          - International Financial Statistics, 1992 (Box 31, Folder 3)
          - Privatization, 1992-1993 (Box 31, Folder 4)
        - Education--Hungarian language education, 1991-1994 (Box 31, Folder 5)
        - European Economic Community (EEC), 1991 (Box 31, Folder 6)
        - Elections
          - General, 1990-1993, (3 Folders) (Box 31, Folder 7-9)
          - Local, 1991 (Box 31, Folder 10)
          - September 1992, 1992 (Box 31, Folder 11)
        - Electoral law, 1990-1992 (Box 31, Folder 12)
        - Embassy, 1992 (Box 31, Folder 13)
        - Emigration, 1990-1993 (Box 31, Folder 14)
        - Environment: General, 1990-1993 (Box 31, Folder 15)
        - Ethnic composition, 1993 (Box 31, Folder 16)
        - Ethnic minorities
          - General, 1972-1988 (Box 31, Folder 17)
          - General, 1989-1994 (Box 32, Folder 1-2)
          - Armenians, 1990 (Box 32, Folder 3)
          - Germans, 1990-1993 (Box 32, Folder 4)
          - Hungarians
            - General, 1989-1994, (4 Folders) (Box 32, Folder 5-8)
            - General, 1994-1995 (Box 33, Folder 1)
            - András Imre, 1991-1992 (Box 33, Folder 2)
            - Bilingualism
              - Catholic Church, 1992 (Box 33, Folder 3)
              - Funar, Gheorghe, 1990-1992 (Box 33, Folder 4)
            - Case files—Killings--1989 December (1989-1992) (Box 33, Folder 5)
            - Census--Judiciary, 1992 (Box 33, Folder 6)
            - Church desecration cases, 1992-1993 (Box 33, Folder 7)
            - Discrimination
              - General, 1985-1993, (2 Folders) (Box 33, Folder 8-9)
              - Satu Mare, 1990-1992 (Box 33, Folder 10)
            - Education, schools, 1990-1993 (Box 34, Folder 1)
            - Harghita (and Covasna) County report, 1991-1993 (Box 34, Folder 2)
            - Hungarian Democratic Federation of Romania (HDFR)-UDMR, 1991-1994 (Box 34, Folder 3)
            - Hungarian Scout Association case, 1990-1991 (Box 34, Folder 4)
            - Hungarian State Opera and Theater in Cluj Napoca, 1992 (Box 34, Folder 5)
            - Káli-Király István, 1992 (Box 34, Folder 6)
            - Language, 1990-1993 (Box 34, Folder 7)
            - Local abuses, 1993 (Box 34, Folder 8)
            - Local administration, 1992-1993 (Box 34, Folder 9)
            - Sulyok István Reformed College, 1992 (Box 34, Folder 10)
            - Szeklers, 1991 (Box 34, Folder 11)
            - Tirgu Mures
              - General, 1985-1992 (Box 34, Folder 12)
              - Cases, 1991-1992 (Box 34, Folder 13)
            - Vatra Romaneasca (Romanian Hearth), 1990-1991 (Box 35, Folder 1)
            - Violent attacks, 1990-1994 (Box 35, Folder 2)
            - Zagon and Zetea cases, 1992-1994 (Box 35, Folder 3)
          - Minority rights, laws, 1991 (Box 35, Folder 4)
          - National Council, 1993 (Box 35, Folder 5)
          - Romanians in Ukraine, 1991 (Box 35, Folder 6)
          - Signs, 1991-1993 (Box 35, Folder 7)
          - Serbs, 1993 (Box 35, Folder 8)
          - Ukrainians, 1993 (Box 35, Folder 9)
        - Film, 1990-1991 (Box 35, Folder 10)
        - Foreign relations
          - General, 1991-1994 (Box 35, Folder 11)
          - Bulgaria, 1994 (Box 35, Folder 12)
          - France, 1991 (Box 35, Folder 13)
          - Germany, 1993-1994 (Box 35, Folder 14)
          - Hungary, 1992-1994 (Box 35, Folder 15)
          - Moldova, 1992-1994 (Box 35, Folder 16)
          - Russia, 1993 (Box 35, Folder 17)
          - Slovakia, 1994 (Box 35, Folder 18)
          - Ukraine, 1994 (Box 35, Folder 19)
          - USSR, 1991 (Box 35, Folder 20)
          - Yugoslavia, 1993 (Box 35, Folder 21)
        - Freedom of assembly
          - General, 1990-1993 (Box 35, Folder 22)
          - Extremist parties, 1992 (Box 35, Folder 23)
        - Freedom of association--violence against demonstrators, 1990 (Box 35, Folder 24)
        - Freedom of press
          - General, 1991-1995 (Box 35, Folder 25)
          - Association of Journalists, 1990 (Box 35, Folder 26)
          - Attacks on journalists, 1990-1992 (Box 35, Folder 27)
          - Audiovisual law, 1990-1993 (Box 35, Folder 28)
          - Defamation, 1994 (Box 35, Folder 29)
          - Economic limitations, 1991-1992 (Box 36, Folder 1)
          - Intimidation, 1991-1994 (Box 36, Folder 2)
          - Law, 1990-1994 (Box 36, Folder 3)
          - Limitations on the press, 1990-1992 (Box 36, Folder 4)
          - Press clippings--freedom of expression and censorship, 1993 (Box 36, Folder 5)
          - State secrets, 1994 (Box 36, Folder 6)
          - TV, 1990-1994 (Box 36, Folder 7)
        - Freedom of speech
          - General, 1990-1994 (Box 36, Folder 8)
          - Economic limitations, 1991 (Box 36, Folder 9)
          - Hate speech, 1991-1992 (Box 36, Folder 10)
        - Government
          - General, 1990-1994 (Box 36, Folder 11)
          - Corruption, 1993-1994 (Box 36, Folder 12)
          - Leadership lists, 1990-1993 (Box 36, Folder 13)
          - Stolojan, Theodor, 1991 (Box 36, Folder 14)
        - Handicapped, 1991 (Box 36, Folder 15)
        - Harghita-Covasna Report--Criminal prosecution of Bishop Tokes, 1990-1993 (Box 36, Folder 16)
        - Health, 1992 (Box 36, Folder 17)
        - Helsinki Watch
          - Correspondence from, 1990-1992 (Box 36, Folder 18)
          - Correspondence from, 1993-1994, (2 Folders) (Box 37, Folder 1-2)
          - Protests, pleas, 1990-1994 (Box 37, Folder 3)
          - Correspondence to, 1990-1995, (3 Folders) (Box 37, Folder 4-6)
            [restricted until 2071]
          - Correspondence with/from Vera Cîmpeanu, 1993-1994 (Box 37, Folder 7)
          - Missions
            - Notebook, 1990-1991, (2 Folders) (Box 37, Folder 8-9)
            - General, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 1)
            - General, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 2)
            - Hadareni case, 1993 (Box 38, Folder 3)
            - Notebooks, 1992-1994, (3 Folders) (Box 38, Folder 4-6)
          - Newsletters and press releases, 1989-1993 (Box 38, Folder 7)
          - Press, 1990-1993 (Box 38, Folder 8)
        - History: Alba Iulia, undated (Box 38, Folder 9)
        - Homosexuals
          - General, 1992-1993 (Box 38, Folder 10)
          - Article 200, 1992-1993 (Box 38, Folder 11)
        - House searches, 1992-1993 (Box 38, Folder 12)
        - Human rights
          - General, 1992-1993 (Box 39, Folder 1)
          - Organizations
            - General, 1990-1992 (Box 39, Folder 2)
            - The League for the Defense of Human Right (LADO), 1991-1994 (Box 39, Folder 3)
            - Non-Romanian--International Helsinki Federation for Human Rights (IHF), 1990-1994 (Box 39, Folder 4)
            - International Human Rights Law Group, 1993 (Box 39, Folder 5)
            - Soros Foundation, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 6)
          - Romanian Helsinki Committee, 1990-1994 (Box 39, Folder 7)
          - Romanian Institute for Human Rights, 1990-1993 (Box 39, Folder 8)
        - Human rights reports, 1992-1994 (Box 39, Folder 9)
        - Iliescu, Ion: General, 1990-1994 (Box 39, Folder 10)
        - Intercultural living in Romania, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 11)
        - International organizations
          - General, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 12)
          - International Monetary Fund (IMF), 1991-1994 (Box 39, Folder 13)
          - Intimidation
            - General, 1991-1992 (Box 39, Folder 14)
            - Attacks against the opposition, 1991 (Box 39, Folder 15)
            - Beatings, 1991 (Box 39, Folder 16)
            - Suspicious arrests, 1991 (Box 39, Folder 17)
        - Jews
          - General, 1991-1993 (Box 39, Folder 18)
          - Anti-Semitism, 1986-1994 (Box 39, Folder 19)
        - June 1990 Events
          - General, 1990-1992 (Box 39, Folder 20)
          - Interviews, 1991 (Box 40, Folder 1)
          - List of arrested protesters, 1990-1991 (Box 40, Folder 2)
          - Report--Group for Social Dialogue and the Romanian Helsinki Committee, 1990 (Box 40, Folder 3)
          - Straulesti Cemetery, 1990 (Box 40, Folder 4)
          - Trials, 1990-1991 (Box 40, Folder 5)
        - Judiciary, 1992-1993 (Box 40, Folder 6)
        - King Michael, 1993 (Box 40, Folder 7)
        - Labor
          - General, 1990-1993 (Box 40, Folder 8)
          - International Labour Office (ILO), 1989-1991 (Box 40, Folder 9)
          - Right to strike, 1991-1993 (Box 40, Folder 10)
          - Trade unions, 1990-1993 (Box 40, Folder 11)
        - Land, 1992-1994 (Box 40, Folder 12)
        - Laws: General, 1990-1992 (Box 40, Folder 13)
        - Legislative activities, 1990-1992 (Box 40, Folder 14)
        - Migration: Bilateral and multilateral treaties, 1993 (Box 40, Folder 15)
        - Military
          - General, 1990-1994 (Box 40, Folder 16)
          - Democratization movement, 1990-1991 (Box 40, Folder 17)
          - Ministry of Defense, 1991 (Box 40, Folder 18)
          - NATO, 1993-1994 (Box 40, Folder 19)
          - Supreme Defense Council, 1991 (Box 40, Folder 20)
        - Ministry of Interior: General, 1990-1992 (Box 40, Folder 21)
        - Opposition
          - General, 1990 (Box 40, Folder 22)
          - Anti-totalitarian Front, 1990 (Box 40, Folder 23)
          - Civic Alliance, 1990-1991 (Box 40, Folder 24)
          - Demonstrations, 1990 (Box 40, Folder 25)
          - Solidarity with workers, 1990 (Box 41, Folder 1)
        - Past Abuses
          - General, 1989-1992 (Box 41, Folder 2)
          - Association “November 15” Brasov, 1990-1991 (Box 41, Folder 3)
          - Lustration, 1991 (Box 41, Folder 4)
          - Minorities, 1991-1992 (Box 41, Folder 5)
          - Police files, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 6)
          - Prosecution
          - General, 1992-1994 (Box 41, Folder 7)
          - Ceausescu’s associates, 1990-1993 (Box 41, Folder 8)
        - Police
          - General, 1990-1994 (Box 41, Folder 9)
          - Democratization efforts, 1990 (Box 41, Folder 10)
          - Excessive use of force, 1991-1994 (Box 41, Folder 11)
        - Political parties
          - General, 1990-1994 (Box 41, Folder 12)
          - Civic Alliance, 1991 (Box 41, Folder 13)
          - Greater Romania Party (PRM), 1991-1993 (Box 41, Folder 14)
          - Liberal Party (PL), 1990-1994 (Box 41, Folder 15)
          - Movement for Romania, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 16)
          - Party of Romanian National Unity (PUNR), 1994 (Box 41, Folder 17)
          - National Salvation Front (FSN), 1991 (Box 41, Folder 18)
          - Party of Social Democracy of Romania (PSDR), 1993 (Box 41, Folder 19)
          - Romanian Communist Party (PCR), 1991-1994 (Box 41, Folder 20)
          - Socialist Labor Party (PSM), 1990-1991 (Box 41, Folder 21)
        - Political prisoners--Amnesties for victims of abuses (under Ceausescu), 1990-1991 (Box 41, Folder 22)
        - Prisons
          - General, 1973-1994 (Box 41, Folder 23)
          - Missions
            - General, 1973-1992, (2 Folders) (Box 42, Folder 1-2)
            - Prison report, 1991 (Box 42, Folder 3)
          - Prison conditions
            - General, 1990-1992 (Box 42, Folder 4)
            - Police lock-ups, 1992-1993 (Box 42, Folder 5)
        - Procurator, 1991-1992 (Box 42, Folder 6)
        - Psychiatric abuse
          - General, 1989-1992 (Box 42, Folder 7)
          - Individual cases, 1974-1991 (Box 42, Folder 8)
        - Publications
          - English, 1974-1985 (Box 42, Folder 9)
          - English, 1988-1989 (Box 43, Folder 1)
          - German, 1990-1991 (Box 43, Folder 2)
          - Romanian, 1977-1981, 1992, (3 Folders) (Box 43, Folder 3-5)
        - Refugees
          - General, 1990-1993 (Box 44, Folder 1)
          - Deportations, 1993 (Box 44, Folder 2)
        - Religion
          - General, 1977-1992 (Box 44, Folder 3)
          - Greek Catholic, 1989-1991 (Box 44, Folder 4)
        - Religious freedom, 1993-1994 (Box 44, Folder 5)
        - Revolution
          - General, 1989-1994 (Box 44, Folder 6)
          - Victims, 1991 (Box 44, Folder 7)
        - Right to privacy and correspondence, 1991-1993 (Box 44, Folder 8)
        - Right wing (Political)--General, 1993-1994 (Box 44, Folder 9)
        - Romanian library, 1991 (Box 44, Folder 10)
        - Romanian monitoring (RFE/RL), 1991 (Box 44, Folder 11)
        - Rome Conference (on human rights, organized by the Italian Helsinki Committee), 1988 (Box 44, Folder 12)
        - Sapînta (Village)--Roadblock and strike, 1990-1992 (Box 44, Folder 13)
        - Securitate
          - General, 1990-1993 (Box 44, Folder 14)
          - Berevoiesti, 1991 (Box 44, Folder 15)
          - Phone tapping, 1990 (Box 44, Folder 16)
          - Security: Law on national security, 1991-1992 (Box 44, Folder 17)
        - SIRDO (Romanian Indep. Society of Human Rights), 1990-1991 (Box 45, Folder 1)
        - Senator Romulus Vulpescu, 1992 (Box 45, Folder 2)
        - Social issues: General, 1993 (Box 45, Folder 3)
        - Soros Foundation: General, 1992-1993 (Box 45, Folder 4)
        - SRI (Romanian Information Services), 1990-1994 (Box 45, Folder 5)
        - Students
          - General, 1990-1991 (Box 45, Folder 6)
          - Strikes, 1990 (Box 45, Folder 7)
        - Tismaneanu, Vladimir, Byzantine Rites: Stalinist Follies: the Twilight (1986) (Box 45, Folder 8)
        - Trials
          - General, 1989-1990 (Box 45, Folder 9)
          - Cseresznyés Pál case, 1990-1992 (Box 45, Folder 10)
          - Oroszhegy (Dealu) case, 1990, (2 Folders) (Box 45, Folder 11-12)
        - United Nations, 1993 (Box 45, Folder 13)
        - United States
          - Bush administration, 1990-1991 (Box 45, Folder 14)
          - Bush report, 1990-1991 (Box 46, Folder 1)
          - Congress
            - Most Favored Nation, 1987-1988 (Box 46, Folder 2)
            - Congressional Human Rights Caucus, 1991 (Box 46, Folder 3)
          - Foreign relations
            - Most Favored Nation, 1990-1993 (Box 46, Folder 4)
            - General, 1990-1994 (Box 46, Folder 5)
          - Laber’s Romania testimony, 1985 (Box 46, Folder 6)
          - Most Favored Nation, 1986-1988 (Box 46, Folder 7)
          - State Department
            - Country reports on human rights, 1991-1992 (Box 46, Folder 8)
            - Critiques of country reports on human rights, 1991-1993 (Box 46, Folder 9)
        - Violent events and demonstrations, 1991 (Box 46, Folder 10)
        - Women: General, 1987-1994 (Box 46, Folder 11)
      - Slovakia
        - List of files (Index), 1994 (Box 47, Folder 1)
        - Helsinki Watch: Mission notebook, 1993 (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Slovenia
        - General, 1991-1992 (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Tajikistan
        - Dushanbe office (Fatimeh Ziai), 1991-1994 (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Yugoslavia
        - Yugoslav Project, 1994 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Subseries II.2: Subject Files
    - General, 1986-1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Albania, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Austria, 1988-1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bibliographies, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Bulgaria, 1985-1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)